Guide to the Grover Lewis Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Unpublished Work, 1958-1995
  - "Mobe March" - Typescript, undated (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - "Movies" - Editorial correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - "Movies" - Typed notes, 1985-1986 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - "Movies" - Typescripts, 1985-1986 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - "Santa Rita" - Typescripts, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - "Their Mouths No Longer Drink" - Typescripts, circa 1958 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Unfinished Work, 1973-1994
    - "All Those Airplanes and Dead People" - Corrected outline, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Edward Anderson - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Edward Anderson - Related material, 1993-1994 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Edward Anderson - Research, 1993-1994 (Box 50, Folder 4-5)
    - Edward Anderson - Notes, 1993-1994 (Box 50, Folder 6-7, Box 51, Folder 1-2)
    - Rod Baines Memoir - Research, circa 1985 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Rod Baines Memoir - Handwritten notes, typescripts, and presentation outline, circa 1985 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Lindsay Bloom - Promo materials and handwritten notes, circa 1977 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Betty Ford Clinic - Editorial correspondence, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Betty Ford Clinic - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Betty Ford Clinic - Research, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Betty Ford Clinic - Handwritten notes, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - The Code of the West - Correspondence, 1982-1993 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - The Code of the West - Related material, 1982-1993 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - The Code of the West - Research, 1982-1993 (Box 52, Folder 8, Box 53, Folder 1-2)
    - The Code of the West - Handwritten and typed notes, 1982-1993 (Box 53, Folder 3-5, Box 54, Box 55, Folder 1-4)
    - The Code of the West - Corrected typescripts, 1982-1993 (Box 55, Folder 5, Box 56, Folder 1-2)
    - The Code of the West - Typescripts, 1982-1993 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Harry Cohn- Handwritten notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - John Connally - Correspondence, circa 1973-1976 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - John Connally - Related material, circa 1973-1976 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Joe Ely - Handwritten notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Max Evans - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Max Evans - Research, 1993 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - William Friedkin - Related material, 1993 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - William Friedkin - Handwritten notes, 1993 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Snuff Garrett - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Snuff Garrett - Related material, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Gatemouth Brown - Handwritten notes, undated (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - Editorial correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - Related material, 1994-1995 (Box 57, Folder 6-7)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - Photographs and other artifacts from Robert Chandler, 1994-1995 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - Photographs from Larry Dennis, 1994-1995 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - Photographs and scanned copies of photographs, 1994-1995 (Box 57, Folder 10-12)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - Research, 1994-1995 (Box 58)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - Handwritten and typed notes, 1994-1995 (Box 59)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - "Oak Cliff Memory" handwritten and typed notes, 1994-1995 (Box 60, Folder 1-10)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - "Lackland Memory" handwritten and typed notes, 1994-1995 (Box 60, Folder 11-12, Box 61, Folder 1-7)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - "Later Events" handwritten and typed notes, 1994-1995 (Box 61, Folder 8-9)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - "Memory" handwritten and typed notes, 1994-1995 (Box 62, Folder 1-6)
    - Goodbye If You Call That Gone - Typed notes and printout of completed pages, 1994-1995 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Tom Hallick - Correspondence and related material, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Howard Hawks Film Festival - Handwritten notes, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Howard Hawks Film Festival - Research and related material, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - John Huston - Research, 1987 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - John Huston - Handwritten and typed notes, 1987 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - "L.A. Law" - Editorial correspondence, 1987 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - "L.A. Law" - Research, 1987 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - "L.A. Law" - Handwritten notes, 1987 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - John Howard Lawson - Handwritten notes and related material, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Lone Pine Film Festival - Research, 1993 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Lone Pine Film Festival - Handwritten notes, 1993 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - The Lost Gonzo Band - Research, 1978 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Carlton E. Morse - Handwritten notes, undated (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Jack Oakie - Handwritten notes and related material, 1978 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Buck Owens - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Buck Owens - Handwritten notes and related material, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Dolly Parton - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Dolly Parton - Handwritten notes, research, and related material, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - Sam Peckinpah - Research, 1992 (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - Sam Peckinpah - Related material, 1992 (Box 63, Folder 20)
    - Slim Pickens - Correspondence, handwritten notes, and research, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - Joan Rivers - Editorial correspondence, 1983 (Box 63, Folder 22)
    - Joan Rivers - Research, 1983 (Box 63, Folder 23)
    - Joan Rivers - Handwritten notes, 1983 (Box 63, Folder 24)
    - Stanley Rose - Research, circa 1978 (Box 63, Folder 25)
    - Demis Roussos - Handwritten notes and research, 1977-1978 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Paul Schrader - Research, 1978 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Martin Scorcese - Handwritten notes, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Martin Scorcese - Transcripts of interviews with Martin Scorcese and Theodora Van Runkle, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Martin Scorcese - Related material, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Billie Joe Shaver - Handwritten notes, undated (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Jim Thompson - Research, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Jim Thompson - Handwritten and typed notes, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Wars - Handwritten notes, undated (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Wars - Corrected typescript fragment, undated (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - John Wayne - Editorial correspondence, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - John Wayne - Handwritten notes, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - John Wayne - Research, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Ricky Don White - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Ricky Don White - Research, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 15)
- Works by Others, 1969-1997
  This series is arranged alphabetically by author and includes mostly photocopied short stories and screenplays. Two notable items relating to Lewis are a forty-six page biography, Grover Lewis: The Uncommon Insight and Grace of an Ordinary Man, written by longtime friend and poet R.K. Scott; and the screenplay Deep Ellum, by Stan Vosper, Jr., based on Lewis's adolescent days with Larry McMurtry and other North Texas friends. Included with the screenplay are several pages of Lewis's handwritten notes and corrections on the screenplay itself.
  - Agee, James, "The Morning Watch", 1951 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Allen, John Houghton, "Always a Brave River", circa 1965 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Anderson, Edward, "Mariana", undated (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, Edward, One Hell...And Many Heavens", undated (Box 65, Folder 4-6)
  - Anderson, Edward, "Savior of the Poor", undated (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Atom Mind, Winter, 1993, Summer, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Babitz, Eve, "The Late Scott Fitzgerald by The Dawn's Early Light", undated (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Barish, Leora, Henry Bean, and Frank Pierson, "Desire", 1980 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Bass, Rick, "Cats and Students, Bubbles and Abysses", 1989 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Bennett, Patrick and Shay, "Culture on the Catclaw: A List of Published Books & Produced Dramas By Abilene Authors", 1994 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Bezzerides, A. I., "There Is A Happy Land", 1947 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Brewton, Pete, "The Mafia, CIA & George Bush" (inscribed), 1992 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Byrum, John, "Beatnik Confidential", undated (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Cameron, Ray and Barry Cryer, "Suicide: The Movie", 1982 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - [Cameron, Ray and Barry Cryer], "Suicide: The Movie," videotape format, undated (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Carr, Roy, Brian Case, and Fred Dellar, "The Hip", 1986 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Carroll, Jon, [untitled], undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Crumley, James, "Whores", 1988 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Delillo, Don, "Libra", 1988 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Didion, Joan, John Gregory Dunne, and Joyce Carol Oates, "January and February", 1972 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Dietz, Lawrence, "Love in Escrow: A Novel", undated (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Disch, Thomas A., "The Joycelin Shrager Story", undated (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Disney, Dorothy Cameron and George Sessions Perry, "Thirty Days Hath September", 1942 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - De Palma, Brian, "Fire", 1984 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Demme, Jonathan, "Among Thieves", undated (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Donaldson, Ross, "Counter-Clockwise Karma"; "The Journals of Tsimis Arcane", undated (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Ellis, S., "The Apartment Contamination", undated (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, "A World Awash With Fascism & Fear", 1971 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Fine, Marshall, "Bloody Sam: The Life and Films of Sam Peckinpah", 1991 (Box 70, Folder 6-7)
  - Fortune, Jan I., ed., "The True Story of Bonnie and Clyde", 1968 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Giancana, Sam and Chuck, "Double Cross", 1992 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Giler, David and Walter Hll, "Southern Comfort", 1980 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Gilmore, Mikal, "Shot in the Dark: The Story of an American Family, in Murder", undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Gordon, Lois and Alan, "American Chronicle", 1987 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Graham, Don, "Doing England,"; "What have They Done to My Town?", 1985, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Gunn, Stephanie C., "Bunny Says It's the Death Watch", 1982 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Haas, Charlie, Martians Go Home"; "The Survival of Van Dyke Parks", 1984, undated (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Hairston, Maxine Cousins, "George Sessions Perry: His Life and Works", 1973 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Hansen, Ron, "Wickedness", 1989 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Hill, Walter, "Chance", undated (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Hill, Walter and Roger Spottiswoode, "The Last Gun", undated (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Hauptman, William, "Kozmic Blues", undated (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Hartman, Charles and L. M. Kit Carson, "A. M.", undated (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Humphrey, William, "Farther Off From Heaven", 1977 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Gordon, Robert, "Annotated Discography, Jazz West Coast: the Los Angeles Jazz Scene of the 1950s", 1986 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Kerouac, Jack, "Visions of Cody", circa 1951-1952 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - King, Stephen, "The Stand", 1984 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Kittredge, William, Owning It All, 1987; "Phantom Silver", 1988 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Le Mieux, Dotty, "The Poet Game"; Niello, 1974 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Lewis, George, "Burner", 1988 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Marrs, Jim. "Crossfire: The Plot That Killed Kennedy", 1989 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - McClintick, David, "Indecent Exposure", 1982 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - McGinniss, Joe, "Heroes", 1976 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Meltzer, R., "Ajax", undated (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Menebroker, Ann and Kell Robertson, "Mailbox Boogie", 1991 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Milburn, George, "Catalogue", 1936 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Minutaglio, Bill and Holly Williams, "The Hidden City: Oak Cliff, Texas" (inscribed), 1990 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Murphy, Tab, "Last of the Dog Men", undated (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Naylor, David, "American Picture Palaces", 1981 (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Nolan, Tom, [untitled], undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Perry, Charles, "From Eternity to Here; What a Long Strange Trip It's Been"; Rolling Stone, February 26, 1976 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Perry, George Sessions, "The Story of Texas A and M", 1951 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Perry, George Sessions, "Tale of a Foolish Farmer" (inscribed), 1951 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Petitclerc, Denne Bart, "Silent Night", 1978 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Pollak, Richard, ed., "Stop the Presses, I Want to Get Off!", 1975 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Porterfield, Nolan, "Home from a War", undated (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Posner, Gerald. "Case Closed" (inscribed), 1993 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Robertson, Kell, The Saga of Thunderlip Jones, Book One, 1969; The Eyes of Jesse James, 1973; When Those Hammers Start to Fall, 1992; Trailer Tramps, 1992; A Horse Called Desperation; Desperado, v. 1, n. 1, 1969, 1973, 1992, undated (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Robertson, Kell, Desperado, v. 1, n. 2; Desperado, v. 2, n. 1; Desperado, n. 3; Desperado, n. 4; Desperado, n. 7; Desperado, n. 8, undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Romero, George A., "Creepshow II", 1984 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Romero, George A., "Day of the Dead", 1984 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Russell, Bud, "The Clyde Barrow – Bonnie Parker Harboring Case", undated (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Russell, Dick, "The Man Who Knew Too Much", 1992 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Sack, John, "Modern Living", undated (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Saunders, Leonard, ["SandyO fer jr."], undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Schiller Productions, Inc., "Country and Western", undated (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Scott, R. K., "Grover Lewis: The Uncommon Insight and Grace of an Ordinary Man", 1997 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Shelby, Carolyn and Christopher Ames, "Men About Town", 1982 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Silke, Jim, "Rascals in Paradise", Issues 1-3, 1994 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - St. Johns, Adela Rogers, "The Honeycomb" (signed), 1969 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Stafford, Jean, "A Mother in History", 1965 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Standish, David, "How I Spent My Spring Vacation", 1977 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Stone, Oliver, "Defiance", undated (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Stone, Oliver, "Platoon", 1984 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Stone, Oliver, "Scarface", undated (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Strauss, Susan, "Sometime I Feel Like a Childless Mother", undated (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Tarantino, Quentin, "Natural Born Killers", 1991; "Reservoir Dogs," 1990, 1990-1991 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Thibeau, Jack, "To Death, With Love, From Poetry"; "Sleeping Pills"; "The Man Who Published in the Sky"; "The Tokyo Rose Kamikaze Pilot"; "A Cub Reporter Takes a Crack at Terry Southern"; "Bombs Over Tokyo"; "The Poetry Repair Kit and Repair Guide: A Testimonial"; "The Secret of Sea Wolf Island", undated (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Viertel, Salka, "The Kindness of Strangers", 1969 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Vosper, Stan Jr., "Deep Ellum", 1986 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Watson, William P., "Union, Justice and Bonnie and Clyde", 1989 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Webb, Walter Prescott, "Texas Rangers", 1993 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Weber, Mark, "Zerx Catalog", 1992 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Weddle, David, "If They Move...Kill 'Em!", 1994 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Wolff, Tobias, ed., "Matters of Life and Death", 1983 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Zigal, Thomas, "Orphan of the West", 1982 (Box 82, Folder 4)
- Audio Tapes
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject and includes both original tapes and listening copies of many of Lewis's taped interviews conducted for L.A. Weekly, Movieline, New West, Oui, and olling Stone magazines. Many famous and prominent actors and artists can be heard, among them Diana Carey (a.k.a. "Baby Peggy"), Elisha Cook, Jr., Larry Flynt (with attempted assassination), David Geffen, Howard Hawks (in a film festival Q & A session), Birney Imes, Lash La Rue, Bette Midler, Robert Mitchum, Slim Pickens, Aldo Ray, Andy Warhol, and Hank Williams, Jr.
  - Terry Allen - Lash La Rue (Box 83)
    Contents
    Terry Allen (2 tapes)
    AM San Francisco: Merle Ellis Grover Lewis, NancyFleming (1 tape)
    Gatemouth Brown, Ida Queen; Count Basie, J. Williams (2 tapes
    )Diana Carey (2 tapes)
    CBS 1977-78 Fall Campaign Music (1 tape, sealed)
    Elisa Cook (4 tapes)
    Bruce David (1 tape)
    Joe Ely (1 tape)
    Larry Flynt (6 tapes)
    Lee Garnes (1 tape)
    David Geffen, Clive Davis (1 tape)
    Stan Dragoti and Charles Moss Press Conference for "Dirty Little Billy" (1 tape)
    Howard Hawks Film Festival (3 tapes)
    Rita Hayworth, Raoul Walsh, Howard Hawks (3 tapes; tapes of Hayworth and Hawks are broken and therefore no listening copy exists)
    Tom Dean Hennessee (1 tape)
    Birney Imes (2 tape)
    KABC Radio: Michael Jackson/Grover Lewis Interview (1 tape)
    Lash La Rue (tapes 1-4)
  - Lash La Rue (continued) - Aldo Ray (Box 84)
    Lash La Rue (tapes 5-10)
    Manhood, etc. (4 tapes)
    Midler (7 tapes)
    Telephone Call from Etta Lee Miller (1 tape)
    Robert Mitchum, Peter Boyle, et al. (6 tapes)
    Jack Oakie (1 tape)
    Ben Pesta (1 tape)
    Ben Pesta/Paul Krassner (1 tape)
    Slim Pickens (3 tapes)
    Aldo Ray (8 tapes)
  - Martin Scorsese; Irwin Winkler, et al.; Thea Van Runkle - Hank Williams, Jr. (Box 85)
    Scope and Contents
    Martin Scorsese; Irwin Winkler, et al.; Thea Van Runkle (3 tapes)
    Billy Joe Shaver (1 tape)
    "Stag Party" (1 tape)
    Unidentified (3 tapes)
    Warhol, Paul Morrissey, Sylvia Miles (2 tapes)
    Jimmy Webb (1 tape)
    Glynn Wolfe (4 tapes)
    Hank Williams, Jr. (2 tapes)
  - Fear and Loathing Promo Tape (reel-to-reel format); Montreal Sessions (reel-to-reel format) (Box 86)
  - Listening copies of original tapes in Box 83 (Box 87)
  - Listening copies of original tapes in Box 84 (Box 88)
  - Listening copies of original tapes in Box 85 and Box 86 (CD format) (Box 89)
- Oversized Items
  Although comprised of various materials and media, photographs and photograph reproductions constitute the bulk of this series. Most of the material here is press/publicity photographs and reproductions relating to Lewis's article for New West magazine, "The Shooting of Larry Flynt: An Eyewitness Account by Grover Lewis." The newspapers (box 91) are Fort Worth Star-Telegram and Fort Worth Press coverage of the Kennedy Assassination
  - Various oversized photographs and artwork, 1970-1975, 1995 (Box 90)
    Oversized photograph of Lawrence Dietz, Grover Lewis, and William Murray in Pacific Palisades Park, Santa Monica, California, taken by Penny Wolin-Semple and signed "Penny"
    Three oversized prints of the Rolling Stone staff, early 1970's by Annie Liebowitz
    Photographic material relating to Larry Flynt: 12 press/publicity photographs and 11 oversized reproductions
    Photograph of Frank and Carole Lalli published in New West magazine
    Mounted photograph, "1972 Houston Livestock Show and Rodeo," signed by Geoff Winningham, dated 3/72
    Large contact photograph of an unidentified man
    Lithograph of lounging lizards by Ralph Steadman
    Newspaper inscribed by James Hayward, "get well Grover," dated 1995
    Mounted poem, "The Donor," by Judee Sill, dated June 6, 1972
    Louisiana State UP shopping bag featuring Confederacy of Dunces
    Statue of Liberty cardboard cut-out measuring approx. 18" x 6"
    Fruit crate label, "Athlete," by Brogdex fruit, Sunkis
  - Fort Worth Star-Telegram and Fort Worth Press newspapers covering the Kennedy Assassination, 1963 (Box 91)